Wall Street is now going
to allow you to trade
GPU hours.
On October 5th, you will
now be able to trade
the price of renting
a graphics card
on the same exchange
that allows you to trade
crude oil.
CME will be listing
these compute futures
on the hourly rental
price of NVIDIA H100
and B200.
Cash settled, listed
on NYMEX.
So why?
The same chip will rent
at around $2 on a Neo
cloud and around $7
on a hyperscaler.
A benchmark makes
the gap visible
and this gap
is tradable.
We do have to watch
whether or not anybody
will actually trade
this 'cause a lot of new
futures contracts will
die of thin liquidity.
So CME Group's Global
Head of energy
and environmental
products says compute
has become the currency
of the AI age.
And the CEO of Silicon
Data says for years, two
companies buying
the exact same GPU
capacity could pay
wildly different prices
with no way to know who
got the better deal.
They will now have
a benchmark to check
that against.